Samuel Fuentes

Caloocan City, Metro Manila snoblefuentes@gmail.com +1 209 498 9737

Summary

As a Full-Stack Blockchain Developer with 5+ years of experience in React, Next.js, Web3.js, Vue.js, Graph, EVM, Solidity, PHP, Laravel, and other technologies, I have developed and delivered various blockchain-based, CRM, SaaS, Fintech applications. My expertise includes web3 integration, smart contract development, decentralized application design, and blockchain integration. With a passion for innovation and problem-solving, I am committed to using my skills and experience to contribute to new and exciting projects in the blockchain industry and your company.

Skills

React.js, Next.js, Web3.js, Node.js, Redux, EVM, Solidity, MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, GraphQL, TypeScript, JavaScript, RESTful APIs, NFT

Experience

Full Stack Engineer

Weave Finance • London, England 11/2021 - 02/2023

- Integrated a lot of the features of the DEFI platform using the Web3.js and Next.js(TypeScript)
- Built staking and liquidity pools and maintain optimal workflow.
- Successfully identified and refactored issues within an existing dapp, resulting in a significant improvement in performance, culminating in an impressive 80% increase at later stages of development.

Sr. Full Stack Developer

Aperture Code Inc • CA 04/2021 - 01/2022

- Collaborated with CTO to successfully manage and deliver Vue.js, Laravel, and Postgresql-based CRM projects for corporate clients.
- Carry out quality assurance tests to discover errors and optimize usability.
- Produced high-impact, user-friendly websites that accomplished all business goals.

Blockchain Developer

Mandox LLC • FL 05/2020 - 05/2021

- Implemented clean interfaces and simple, intuitive interactions for NFT Marketplace using React TypeScript and Web3.js.
- Minting, deploy and sale 100000 NFTs and created smart contract.

Full Stack Developer

Vcomp Inc • Toronto, ON 04/2019 - 05/2020

- Responsible for full stack web development for all client projects.
- Increased customer satisfaction by 35% and customer retention by 40%.

Laravel and React.js Developer

QuizGriz • CA 06/2017 - 02/2019

• Built efficient, testable, and reusable Laravel modules.

- Solved complex performance problems and architectural challenges.
- Integration of REST API, implemented SPA frontend using Vue.js
- Defined and developed MVC, REST, Hybrid (MVC+REST combined) applications.
- Operated in team-based, Scrum environment to accomplish objectives quickly and efficiently.
- Analyzed code and debugged errors to improve system performance.

Education

Computer Science

University of Caloocan City 03/2016

Received the Bachelor of Science in Computer Science program in 2016

Objective

To secure a Full Stack developer role where I can utilize my skills in TypeScript, React.js, Next.js, Web3.js, and Node.js to design and develop innovative software applications.

Service

Fully Responsible | Idea Contributor | Complex problem solver | Clean Code | Creative design | Innovative | Service focused | Well-Organized | Critical Thinking | Problem-Solving | Detail-oriented | Multi-tasking | Teamwork

Github Link

https://github.com/chamisg

Latest Work History

Weave Finance

During my time at Weave Financial, I gained valuable experience in systems architecture and full-stack web development. Working alongside the CTO, I played a key role in designing a new Defi website. Specifically, I oversaw the creation of systems architecture utilizing frameworks such as Next.js, React.js, Web3.js, and TypeScript. Additionally, I successfully identified and refactored issues within an existing dapp, resulting in a significant improvement in performance, culminating in an impressive 80% increase at later stages of development.